Vishal. S. Hiremani

MECHANICAL ENGINEER

💡 #164, Deepthi Nivas, 2nd Cross, Vijaya Bank Colony, Basavanapura Main Raod K.R. Puram, Bangalore:560036

💌 shreeshial.hiremani@hotmail.com/盲: +91-9566257209

I am a mechanical engineer with 8 years of experience and core competencies in Hydraulic application Engineering, Design of hydraulic system by selection of hydraulic elements for hydraulic power pack based on application, Hydraulic power pack testing (QA - Outgoing) based on application and quality requirement, Maintenance and servicing of hydraulic system.

Work Experience

Assistance Manager (Maintenance)

01 Sep 2 0 2 1 - 0 9 Feb 2 0 2 2

Jindal aluminium Ltd (Bangalore, India)

The Job role involved in handling, servicing and maintenance of Hydraulic aluminium extrusion press, design upgradation and retro fitment of hydraulic systems, attending breakdown maintenance, preventive maintenance of hydraulic press, profile puller, runouts, profile stretcher, profile cutting machine, pumping unit for cooling towers, Baling press, online oil filters & Ageing furnace.

Deputy Manager (Service)

23 Sep 2019 - 23 June 2020

Godrej & Boyce Mfg. Co, Ltd (Mumbai, India)

The Job role involved in handling servicing and maintenance of mobile autonomous launcher for Brahmos Missiles launchers for AMC & NON-AMC site across India. To coordinate and Handling enquires from Brahmos, providing quotation for the spares, arranging required spare for the site by ensuring delivery of the spare with in stipulated period of time, Deputing service engineer for AMC & NON-AMC site. Follow up and getting clearance for the work carried out at site from defence higher official. Since being experienced in the field of hydraulics was used to attend & resolve the hydraulic issues, Coordinating with design department for any design upgradation and retro fitment,

Senior Engineer (MDS, System Integration) 8 Mar 2018-15 Dec 2018

L&T Technology Services Pvt Ltd (Chennai, India)

This role involved in providing designing and integration of hydraulic piping has per the circuit for HUB & Nacelle system in wind turbine, to develop hydraulic circuit has per the functional requirement which is used in the application of pitching and wind turbine blades and Breaking system of the wind turbine rotor for maintenance purpose using Creo 4.0 and windchill has PDM base for customer Vestas.

Senior Lead Engineer

09 J u n 2 0 1 6 - 1 7 0 c t 2 0 1 6

FLSmidth Pvt Ltd (Chennai, India)

This role involved in Servicing, Maintenance, Commissioning, Trouble shooting and retro fitment of hydraulic system in Cement Industries to carry out MOM and spare management.

Raw Mill Lime hydraulic lime stone crusher, Kiln Hydraulic thrust device, CB & SF Cooler closed loop pump hydraulic system, Atox & Ok Mill hydraulics (VRM Hydraulic Crushers), Truck tippler, Wagon tippler, Side arm charger, Inhaul wheel gripper, exit wheel gripper, Pusher car are the hydraulic system handled for servicing & commissioning during my service in FL Smidth Pvt Ltd.

Engineer

17 Jul 2013 - 06 Jan 2016

UTC Aerospace Systems Pvt Ltd (Bangalore, India)

The role was involved in Designing, Develop, modify & maintain hydraulic test rig for the testing C-Series PDOS, MRJ DOS, A-320 Neo DOS, A350 PDOS, 787 PDOS & (777 -X PDOS***) Actuator and Power Pack as per the production acceptance test procedure. Carry out calibration activity in house or by third party vendor as per aerospace standards. Developed in house Calibration for Pressure transducer and Position sensor for MRJ Elevator Actuator rig. Carry out total preventive maintenances for all the production supporting equipment's. Carry out periodic check for oil contamination. Supporting FAI & supporting SCM in sourcing the vendors suitable to carry out the activity. Develop work instruction for machines and equipment's. Carry out Continuous improvement of the test rig. Upgrade the rig has per the test requirement in terms of design.

Was the part of Refurbishment of **MRJ Elevator Actuator Project restart.** The entire test rig was redesigned, redeveloped and retro fitted as per production acceptance test using **CATIA V5.** Ensure zero leakage by upgrading the rig seals compactable for SKYDROL Hydraulic oil. 60 TR Chiller was refurbished for the same. The test rig was validated from our team and counterpart from France and the customer and released to production acceptance test and released for production by creating new testing procedure.

Junior Executive Engineer

Apr 2 0 1 0 - Jul 2 0 1 3

Yuken India Ltd (Bangalore, India)

Joined Yuken India Ltd has a trainee in the design department where I was trained to design a hydraulic circuit based on the application, I was trained to design hydraulic circuit and Assembly drawing using **Auto Cad, Auto Desk Inventor and Solid Edge Software's.**

My role was involved in designing of hydraulic system based on application for Machine tool, Hydel powerplant, steel plant and SPM hydraulic system.

Later I was transferred to QA Outgoing my role was involved in Caring out overall performance testing of hydraulic power pack as per the quality standards and customer standards. Handling customer and 3rd party inspection of the machine. Certification of the machine. Conduct hydraulic training classes in group at Yuken India hydraulic School. Trouble shooting and servicing of hydraulic power packs and its elements like pump and valves.

Internship / Engineering Project

Yuken India Ltd (Bangalore, India)

The aim of the project was to design, develop & validate a hydraulic power pack system for a scrap compacting machine to effectively reduce the transportation cost & reduce the storage place to store the scrap. This machine is used to compact the mild steel and stainless scrap effectively in a scrap compacting box of dimension of 40Cms in length (Stroke length), Breath and Height of 30Cms using a double acting cylinder. The hydraulic circuit, designing and manufacturing was done in Yuken India Ltd under the guidance of the project guide.

The operating pressure of the system was set to 60Bar using a Variable displacement vane pump. 25Bar pressure is used to compact the scrap effectively with the help of pressure reducing valve. Manifold was designed and developed as per the requirement, Strainers & filters was selected and used as per the requirement under the guidance of project guide from Yuken India Limited.

Qualifications

Bachelor of Engineering – Mechanical Engineering M. V Jayaraman College of Engineering (Bangalore, India) affiliated to VTU Belgaum.

2005-2009

Skills

- ♦ Very strong oral & written communication skills
- ♦ Proven ability to work well both within a team and independently.
- ♦ Hydraulic power pack design based on Application, Testing, Servicing, Commissioning & Maintenance.
- ♦ Calibration of instruments and Documentation.

Place: Bangalore, India

Yours Sincerely,

Vishal.S. Hiremani